(Music)
My name is Gary Feierabend.
I’m the Head of Engineering Transformation in Canada
and responsible for launching Manulife University globally.
My area deals with the agile practices,
the engineering cadre, and security engineering of how
we do things in Manulife.
My team is made up of several functions.
The first part of it is Manulife University.
Manulife University is really about what we call
an upskilling and mastering program.
At Manulife, in the beginning it was very difficult
to maintain our ability to stay up to date on
technologies, anything to adopt modern stacks.
In order to establish programs working with Pluralsight,
Manulife University for campus-based training or
virtual-based training to really ramp up engineers
of how we get things done is a critical aspect of what we do.
But there’s another important side, and that is how we
also demonstrate, can you apply those skills that
you’ve learned back into the squad or back into the
projects that you’re working on.
One of the challenges I think that Pluralsight Flow
really helped us to realize was prior to us introducing
Flow in our organization, we just didn’t have enough
data, so we were just really looking at burndown rates
and number of stories completed, but it didn’t give us
the context of what our engineering teams were really focused on.
We are customer obsessed. We find that the best way
to be customer obsessed is to be obsessed about our
engineers and our employees.
Since we’ve started leveraging Flow, we are able to start
finding optimizations in terms of how frequently we
are committing code, making sure that we’re doing
more effective code reviews, and that all relates to
better code quality.
Flow data is power. Some of the major benefits that
I got with Flow is to learn based on data.
In my case, the sessions that I had with my manager
were very insightful. I learned that maybe I should be
taking more time on looking for opportunities to
create new features rather than maybe looking at
that legacy code. So I think by having these conversations,
by looking at those metrics, we have an opportunity for
not only knowing what is happening on our development
cycles, but to learn and to enhance that development process.
Skills from Pluralsight was a very valuable asset
because we recognized people needed to learn at
their frequency, their times, but there was one much
more important aspect to Skills.
Role IQ and Skill IQ removes the bias that exists
within organizations about who would be a good
front-end engineer or data engineer or data scientist.
It’s much more quantifiable data, and now we can
use it in promotional material to get that person
to the next level of their career.
We had one beautiful example.
We found an individual that was at the associate
level for five years, yet this associate level,
through Skill IQ and again through Flow,
helped identify how much they really get done on
the squad, but they just don’t happen to be verbal
about it, they don’t happen to stand up at the retro
and really showcase what they’re able to do.
Instead of releases that were once a quarter,
we’ve started releasing once a month,
and then now releasing every sprint,
releasing features, new product evolutions
because they gain skills, they’re transparent in terms
of what’s happening within the squad and what
are the blockers that they’re running into and
what’s causing churn. It leads to a better product,
and the product our customer sees.